Guide to the Sunnyside Gardens Preservation Alliance records, 1988-2014.
Sunnyside Gardens Preservation Alliance records
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Sunnyside Gardens Preservation Alliance records, 1988-2014.
6910
Sunnyside Gardens Preservation Alliance.
.3 cubic feet.
Correspondence, Manuscripts, Printed Materials, Publications, Reports
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Records from the inception of the Sunnyside Gardens Preservation Alliance (2003) to the completion of their quest for Landmarks designation (2007); items from Oral History program.
ORGANIZATIONAL HISTORY
Neighborhood organization "dedicated to the preservation and revitalization of the Sunnyside Gardens National Register Historic District."
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Records from the inception of the Sunnyside Gardens Preservation Alliance (2003) to the completion of their quest for Landmarks designation (2007). Includes Sunnyside Gardens Historic District Designation Report by the New York City Landmarks Preservation Commission, June 26, 2007.
CDs and typescript summaries from the Sunnyside Gardens Oral History program include interviews by Herbert Reynolds with Nesbitt Garmendia (2012), Robert W. Jones (2012), Marilyn Lutzker (2012), Gerry Modica (2012), and Ethel Plimack (2010); interview by Herbert Reynolds and Tony Rohling with Gerry Modica and Suzanne Patterson (2010); and interviews by Sabine Heinlein with Dorothy A. Cavallo (2011) and Liivia Westervelt (2011). Also two interviews by Pamela Nelson with Gerald A. Perrin (1988).
SUBJECTS
Names:
Sunnyside Gardens Preservation Alliance.; Stein, Clarence S.; New York (N.Y.).Landmarks Preservation Commission.
Subjects:
Historic districts--New York (State)--New York.; Architecture--New York (State)--New York.; Historic buildings--New York (State)--New York.
Places:
Sunnyside Gardens (New York, N.Y.)
INFORMATION FOR USERS
SERIES LIST
Series I. Landmarks Preservation Campaign
Series II. Sunnyside Gardens Oral History Program
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Landmarks Preservation Campaign
  - The heart of this collection-- all the flyers and newsletter produced by the SGPA and delivered to every household in Sunnyside Gardens. On occasion, this folder includes a message from a supporter or affiliate of the SGPA or an item delivered to a narrower group of supporters. Manila folder., n.d. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Copies of cards collected door to door within Sunnyside Gardens, chiefly during 2005. The aim was to reach property owners in order to show that an absolute majority supported designation. (Majority support is not a requirement for designation, but as so many owners were demonstratively in favor, this was evidence to expedite the political process by assuring elected officials.) These cards also include many tenants and enabled the SGPA to build its e-mail and phone networks of supporters in this campaign. The cards exclude the earliest supporters in Harrison Place, who had already voiced their support in the petition below. On legal paper., 2005 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Cover sheet containing "RESOLUTION". May 2003 petition from Harrison Place, a large homeowners association within Sunnyside Gardens that was the first to determine and declare the support of the great majority of its members-- in effect prompting the formation of the SGPA as the neighborhood-wide organization to conduct the campaign toward designation., 2003 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - "To the Landmarks Preservation Commission... We the undersigned..." A general petition, intended for use outside of Sunnyside Gardens, although it includes some signatures from residents of the neighborhood., n.d. (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Testimony-- in those cases where copies were shared with the SGPA-- that was sent to the New York City Landmarks Preservation Commission (LPC) for its April 17, 2007, Public Hearing on Sunnyside Gardens. Reprints of e-mails [first page headed with "A sampling of written testimony..."] are followed by photocopies of letters. Pursuant to this hearing, the Commissioners voted to designate the Sunnyside Gardens Historic District on June 24, 2007, and the matter was referred to the Department of City Planning and the City Council., 2006-2007 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Headed "C - General Information." Testimony-- again, where this was shared with the SGPA-- from the August 8, 2007, Public Hearing before the Department of City Planning (also known as the City Planning Commission), whose Commissioners hear and then vote their approval or disapproval of LPC's designated historic district., 2007 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Two individual pages add some amplification to the above. A letter from the SGPA, dated June 11, 2006, addressed to the Chairman of the LPC, sums up the level of support (as yet incomplete at that date), implicitly to urge the LPC to place Sunnyside Gardens on its formal calendar for designation. The other page, headed "from the LPC's... page 3" (reprinting the LPC's summary of its Public Hearing to consider Sunnyside Gardens' designation), served as a cover sheet for supporting materials, like those above, which were delivered to members of the City Council in anticipation of their vote to affirm or overturn the LPC's designation at the conclusion the designation process in early Fall 2007., 2006-2007 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Flyers produced by the opponents of Landmarks designation, Dec. 2006 to Spring 2007. As generally happens during the formal process, once the LPC mails a procedural letter to every property owner announcing its interest in designation and then holds a public meeting within the proposed historic district (the Sunnyside Gardens meeting was on November 29, 2006), opponents are aroused, come to know each other at the meeting, and begin an opposition campaign., 2006-2007 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Sunnyside Gardens Historic District, designation report, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Sunnyside Gardens 1924-2014 90th Birthday, 2014; DVD-3251 (Box 1)
- Series II. Sunnyside Gardens Oral History Program
  - Oral History Program, 2012 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Oral History Program, document disc, 2012; CD-1654 (Box 1)
  - Mary Caulfield interview, 2013; CD-4954 (Box 1)
  - Dorathy A. Cavallo interview, 2011; CD-1511 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Herbert Danska interview, 2011; CD-4949 (Box 1)
  - Herbert Danska interview, 2011; CD-4950 (Box 1)
  - Nesbitt Garmendia interview, 2012; CD-1652 (Box 1)
  - Robert Jones interview, 2012; CD-1651 (Box 1)
  - Marilyn Lutzker interview, 2012; CD-1512 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Gerry Modica, 1st interview, 2010; CD-1649 (Box 1)
  - Gerry Modica, 2nd interview, 2012; CD-1650 (Box 1)
  - Gerald Perrin interview, parts 1 and 2, 1988; CD-1647 (Box 1)
  - Gerald Perrin interview, parts 3 and 4, 1988; CD-1648 (Box 1)
  - Ethel Plimack interview, 2010; CD-1513 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Joan Vitolo-Curan interview, 2013; CD-4951 (Box 1)
  - Susan Vladeck interview, 2012; CD-4953 (Box 1)
  - Liivia Westervelt interview, 2011; CD-1653 (Box 1)
  - Liivia Westervelt interview, 2013; CD-4952 (Box 1)